http://3rdupminsterscouts.org.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy Statement
Our website address is: http://3rdupminsterscouts.org.uk.
The Scout Association takes the issue of privacy very seriously and is committed to protecting and respecting our users’ privacy online. This Privacy Statement sets out our current data processing practices and should be read in conjunction with our terms and conditions. If you have any queries or concerns regarding these practices, you should contact us at info.centre@scout.org.uk.
1. The information we collect
The only circumstances in which we will provide any of your personal data to a third party for non commercial purposes are those contained in this Privacy Policy.
2. Registration information
When you register with www.scouts.org.uk, we ask for your name, email address and postcode. We usually also capture your IP address at the time you register.
3. Sharing of data
We may share data supplied by you (or collected about you) with other parts of The Scout Association eg Scout Shops Ltd. Donating to The Scout Association – We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any third parties with regard to any donation you make to The Scout Association.
4. Advertising
www.scouts.org.uk may include interactive advertising for other businesses as part of the site operation. We may use, and provide to third parties, your contact details if you have given us permission to do so.
5. Legal jurisdiction
All personal information and details held on and processed by computers situated in the United Kingdom.
6. Further information
www.scouts.org.uk will as part of it’s normal operation send out to information emails. Members can decide to ask for these emails as they register.
7. Disclosure of data by order of a Court and Security
We reserve the right to communicate a Member’s personal information as we hold to third parties who are empowered by regulation, statute or order of a court.
We have security measures in place to protect our customer database. Access to this database is restricted internally. However, it remains each Member’s responsibility:
to keep their password secret
to protect against unauthorised access to your personal details
to log off from the www.scouts.org.uk service when not using it; and
to ensure against use by anyone else of the www.scouts.org.uk Service through the machine that Member uses while they are “logged on” to the www.scouts.org.uk service
to search and obtain only the data specifically required and allowed for relating to their role.
8. Use of cookies by The Scout Association
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site
The table below explains the cookies we use and why.
Cookie
Name
Purpose
More information
Google Analytics
_utma
_utmb
_utmc
_utmz
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google
Module cookie
Module_layout1
module_layout2
module_layout3
module_open
These cookies are used to store your personal homepage layout of the Scouts.org.uk home page.
We are working towards developing a new system that will remove the need for this Cookie.
Session cookies
res_width
res_height
PHPSESSID
These cookies are used to optimise you screen resolution for user logged in areas. These are session cookies and only last as long as you browser is open
These cookies are essential to the running of the site and member areas.
Style cookie
style
This cookies determines you default font size for Scouts.org.uk. On the main menu of Scouts.org.uk you can increase or decrease you font size.
We are working towards developing a new system that will remove the need for this Cookie.
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
YouTube cookies
We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit YouTube’s embedding videos information page.
9. The Data Protection act
You can obtain further information about data protection laws by visiting the Information Commissioner’s website at http://ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection.
10. Contacting www.scouts.org.uk
If you want to contact us to raise any questions about this privacy statement, or any general matters relating to www.scouts.org.uk, you can contact us using this email address: info.centre@scout.org.uk.
Please use this address if you wish to request from us a copy of the personal data we hold about you. Please note that under English law we are entitled to charge you a fee for providing this service.
11. Google Analytics
Visitors to this website who have javascript enabled are tracked using Google Analytics. Google Analytics collects the following types of information from users:
Type of user agent (web browser) used, software manufacture and version number.
Type of operating system
Screen colors (color processing ability of the users screen)
Javascript support
Flash version
Screen resolution
Network location and IP address
Can include country, city, state, region, county, or any other geographic data.
Hostname
Bandwidth (internet connection speed)
Time of visit
Pages visited
Time spent on each page of the website
Referring site statistics
The website (URI) the user came through in order to arrive at this website (example: clicking on a hyperlink from Yahoo.com that took the user to this website)
Search engine query used (example: typing in a phrase into a search engine like Google, and clicking on a link from that search engine)
This data is only used to optimise our website for our visitors.
This data DOES NOT include any personalised identification information such as:
Names
Phone numbers
Email addresses
Mailing addresses
Bank account numbers
Credit card information
The Scout Association Data Protection Policy can be found here. Also, to get in contact with The Scout Association with regards to a Subject Access Request (SAR), please email legal.services@scouts.org.uk.
Share this page
Print this page
Email a friend
Share on Facebook
Share on Twitter
About us
Mission statement
News (RSS)
© 3rdupminsterscouts.org.uk, all rights reserved | Charity number: XXXXXX
Powered by WordPress | Scouts 4 WordPress theme by Scouting Themes 4 WordPress
